Guide to the Central Washington University Library Department, Brooks Library Building Papers 1962-2011
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Library Department, Brooks Library Building Papers
1962-2011
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG011-05-13
Central Washington University Library
1.25 cubic foot 2 letter-sized boxes, 1 half letter-sized box Correspondence, plans, meeting minutes, photographs and working papers in good condition
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, sketches, drawings, specifications, and photographs relevant to the construction of Brooks Library at Central Washington University, 1962-2011.
Historical Note
The Central Washington University library began in Barge Hall, moved into Bouillon Hall when it was constructed, and finally to a new building in 1973. The architect of the new library building was Ibsen Nelson of Seattle. The library was initially part of a Library-Instructional Complex that included another building attached to the library via a breezeway which would have contained the Anthropology, Sociology and Psychology departments as well as general use classrooms. In 2003, the building was named in honor of Dr. James L. Brooks, former president of Central Washington University.
Along with meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, sketches, and drawings, this collection contains correspondence between Central Washington University library staff, building committee members, architects, and other construction personnel.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Arranged chronologically and alphabetically by subject.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University. Library
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; College buildings
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- 1962-1967 (Box-folder 1-1)
- 1968 (Box-folder 1-2)
- 1969 (Box-folder 1-3)
- 1970 (Box-folder 1-4)
- 1971 (Box-folder 1-5)
- 1972 (Box-folder 1-6)
- 1973 (Box-folder 1-7)
- 1974 (Box-folder 1-8)
- 1975 (Box-folder 1-9)
- 1976 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Strategic planning, 1995-2010 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Library history display for National Library Week, 2011 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Undated Papers (Box-folder 3-1)
- Card Catalog Deficiencies (Box-folder 3-2)
- Photographs (Box-folder 3-3)
- Schematic Drawings, June 28, 1968 (Box-folder 3-4)
- August 9, 1968 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Schematic Drawings, 1970 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Specifications (Box-folder 3-7)
- Specifications Addendum (Box-folder 3-8)
- Specifications- Architectural, Structural (Box-folder 3-9)